Many years ago, mankind faced a divine fury.
In an event known as the Day of the Cataclysm,
our entire world was burned.
The fire raged with an intensity
that threatened to reduce mankind to ash.
The places they lived, the languages they spoke,
the culture they had built,
none could escape its wrath.
Haran has returned to the flame.
He died a martyr.
It was a small price to pay for the birth of a new demon.
No regrets.
Also, the boy from Company 8 with an Edole burst
experienced an Edole link with the demon.
Then that settles it.
Yes, we must acquire him.
For the evangelist wills it.
It's a waste for the Fire Force to have an asset like that.
There may be more to this than it seems.
I'll go along next time.
A new team member coming out of nowhere?
It seems kind of sudden, don't you think?
Hajima a strong-armed one of their people through
since the 8th doesn't have its own science team.
They're plotting something.
That's a little harsh.
After the whole evangelist incident,
every company is under Imperial order
to step up their scientific investigations, right?
I know we've been lagging a bit in that area,
but we were searching out new members.
In the meantime, Captain Hibana has been providing us
with all the support we need.
Yeah, but that's a bit of a bad habit to get into,
and I'm sure a captain like her
has plenty on her plate already.
Hajima saw a problem and offered me as a solution.
Therefore, I will now be serving
as Special Fire Force Company 8's head scientist.
The name's Victor Leaked.
Take what you got and leave now.
You're wearing out, you're welcome.
No one here wants to see you, hear you.
Think that you won from day one,
but then the devil will come.
You know just why he wants you, don't you?
You're crooked, desire, left us in history.
Misguided, defighted, in the part of the reason.
You started a fighter, you're gonna watch it burn.
Try to save yourself like you always do.
Every bridge we bow, you think it's just a burn it down.
Just burn it down, when everything is gone.
You wish you only hurt us out, hurt us out.
Screaming, METE!
METE!
It smells like a rat if you ask me.
A proper Fire Force salute should be performed with the right hand, not the left one.
Oh, uh, not really my thing?
I'm sorry.
Oh, scientists, right?
Head in the clouds.
Oh.
I don't, my curiosity!
I don't have to see you.
What are you doing?
Show me.
Don't get touchy-feely with him.
Yes, ma'am.
My boy!
Victor leaked.
Let's see.
Advanced placement into Tokyo Imperial University.
Graduated at the top of your class.
Headed the applied pyrokinesiology lab at Hyjima Heavy Industries.
I must admit, it's quite the resume.
Hmm.
What can I say?
I'm brilliant.
More like suspiciously brilliant.
This place is a dump.
Why would you want to work here?
Hyjima kept me cooped up in my lab all the time, and it was starting to get stale.
I thought if I joined an outfit closer to the action, I might be able to get some intriguing
new data out of the front lines, so to speak.
If I cause any trouble, you can kick me out.
But at least let me join for now.
Looking at your staff list, I'm a little worried.
You guys don't have an engineer yet, do you?
It's nice that you have a researcher now, but are any of you qualified to service your vehicle?
You gotta take care of that stuff.
Yeah, that's on the agenda.
We have someone in mind already.
Lieutenant, have you been able to reach him?
Vulcan?
He hasn't replied.
You're trying to recruit Vulcan?
Are you taking this seriously at all?
Should I know him?
The point is that nobody can recruit him.
Hyjima, the special fire force, he turns them all away in an instant.
But I'll tell you, Vulcan's the real deal.
He's a true god of the forge, just like his namesake.
We may have to make a personal trip to his workshop if we want to get through to him.
I don't think that's gonna work out for you.
He hates Hyjima with a passion, and he hates the fire force as much for working with him.
He'll send you packing like everyone else.
Okay, then.
Shinra, I want you to head to Vulcan's workshop, take Iris and Arthur with you.
Before we move forward with anything, I need to know if this guy's company ate material.
You think we're good to make that call?
Why do you want to send us three?
Vulcan is about your age, so you might get along.
Keep it casual, keep it honest, and don't let him think you're trying too hard.
Yes, sir!
I don't want this to be too formal, so it's better if you go in your civvies.
That doesn't mean you need to be cagey about who you are, though.
If we come across as deceptive, he won't trust us.
Just try to say hello.
If all the stories are true, that may be hard enough.
We'll show him some guts!
The other company's tried to tempt Vulcan with promises of money.
Or status.
The Eighth is just sending kids.
I told you, Vulcan loathes the Fire Force.
This is a total waste of your time.
We're trying to change the world here.
We gotta do the impossible.
Let's try and see what happens.
I just got here and things are getting interesting already.
Well, this should be as good a test as any.
Let's see if you can help us reach our goals or not.
Company Eight.
I've seen that animal in a picture book.
The big one with the long snout.
Yeah, it's called an elephant, right?
That's it.
I think.
This place is really something.
Excuse me!
Maybe he's not at home.
Or he's just ignoring us.
I am the Night King!
Arthur Boyle!
Fire Soldier!
How audacious of you to disrespect the Night King!
It's the Fire Soldier part he didn't like!
Get lost!
Ow-hey!
Slow-witted dolt.
Ow!
Stop screwing with us and come out!
You think your feeble projectiles intimidate me?
Um, hello.
Can I help you?
Ah, Atom.
I'm sorry for being so rude.
We're here from Special Fire Force Company Eight.
I'm Shinra Kusakabe.
First Class Fire Soldier.
And I'm a hero, too.
Another visit from another Fire Force Company, huh?
You're here to recruit the Master, but he won't let you in, I assume.
Hello? Master?
I've returned with the parts you asked for.
Yeah, I told you not to call me Master, remember?
It's either Vulcan or Dirtbag.
Take your pick.
Vulcan, then.
But anyway, um, the parts that you needed are in that bag.
Hold on, Dirtbag!
Ah!
Aw.
Enough like the can't-
Huh?
What?
There's a second can of salient?
I have nothing to say to you Fire Soldiers.
Buzz off!
He really doesn't like us, huh?
Although I guess we were warned.
We didn't even say anything, and he's already picking a fight.
Let's go.
This isn't gonna work.
Hold on a sec.
I'll hear you out, if you guys will talk to me.
It almost sounds like he's playing drums in there.
Did Vulcan make all this crazy stuff lying around?
Yeah, pretty much.
There's projects from his father and grandfather, too.
Wait, and you bring him parts?
Is he forcing you to do all his busy work?
He doesn't have to force me.
I want to.
It's not like official, but, uh, I'm sort of Vulcan's apprentice.
I've always liked tinkering with machines, and I admire Vulcan's work.
So I asked him if I could lend a hand around the workshop.
That was the plan, but I'm mostly running errands now.
So did something happen to change things?
Vulcan's talent is the real deal.
His work shows precision, speed, and above all else, creativity.
He's the ultimate technician, with no weak points.
I'm not really into the whole skull thing, but whatever.
Anyway, as you can imagine, he's in high demand, from Heijima and you guys.
But Vulcan turns everyone away on the spot.
Heijima wasn't too happy about this, of course, so they pulled some strings.
And now, no more merchants will work with him.
He can't get materials anywhere.
But I've been able to get him most of the parts he needs by running around to different junk shops.
I guess I'd hate Heijima, too, if I were him.
I don't know.
He hates Heijima and the Fire Force a lot.
I haven't heard the details, but it's quite the grudge.
Trust me, we aren't like the other companies.
You have my word on that.
Please, can you at least ask Vulcan to hear us out?
Just this once.
Maybe you're right.
I have to admit, you're nothing like the others who came to recruit him.
I'll take you in.
It's worth a shot.
Should we just barge in without asking?
Vulcan might yell at me about it, but it'll be fine.
Wait, it was a machine all along.
Owie!
Another one?
How many?
Actually, that one was thrown by Lisa.
She lives here with Vulcan.
Yeah, come on!
You know better than to let the Fire Force in here!
My arm, you're breaking it!
I don't know about all the banging, but he's fast.
I've never seen that technique before.
All right, it's done!
Why would you kick something you just made across the floor?
What if it breaks?
A machine that breaks from one kick is defective, far as I'm concerned.
Hey, you little rats!
Who invited you in here?
We want to talk, that's all.
Hey, yeah!
What are you doing?
Bring some drinks already!
Oh, thank you.
Yeah, right!
Just five minutes, okay?
I heard enough from the Fire Force to last a lifetime.
So get your ass out of my shop!
Moron.
Vul, looks like he's back.
I'll handle it.
Are you okay alone?
It'll be fine.
That's the Captain of the Third.
Their company is in tight with Heijima.
Does that mean they're gonna nab Vulcan before us?
No way.
If Vulcan goes with them,
there's no way his dream will ever come true.
How has business been these days?
Slow, it seems.
You still have a fondness for animals,
like when you were a child.
That was a dirty trick you pulled!
I know you're the one who cut me off from my suppliers!
You think that's gonna work?
I needed to teach you it takes more than blueprints to build something.
Stop being stubborn and join us.
I assure you, you'll have all the materials you could ever dream of.
I wouldn't even change a light bulb for your filthy company!
This is your final warning, Vulcan.
If you fail to heed it, you can only blame yourself.
What, you gonna kill me?
Like you did with my dad and my granddad?
What are you talking about?
Piss off, you backstabber!
Such a pity.
All your talent wasting away in this scrapyard when you could accomplish so much more.
Speaking of wasteful, your plan with the animals will never work.
Shut up!
A child's dream.
You sold off all your dreams for money and power!
What the hell do you know?!
You're not being bold, you're being selfish.
If you offered your talents to the Empire, imagine how many lives could be saved.
Your dream is worthless.
It's too pathetic to even laugh at.
What's your problem?
I thought I told you to get out of here.
Sure it was smart to piss off Heijima like that?
It's not your problem either way.
Actually, it is.
The Eighth was formed to investigate the Fire Force from the inside.
We're not like the other companies who were tied down by big organizations.
The only thing we care about is helping people.
So talk to us.
Maybe we can help you too.
Who turned that thing on?
Oops.
Guess I must have touched it someplace weird.
We're having a serious conversation here.
Stop touching things in weird places.
What does this button do?
Nothing good.
Don't press it.
What's your deal?
Hey, how do you get this thing to stop?
Don't ask me.
What's this one do?
Get away from there!
Boom.
The Allopants!
What does this little round guy do?
Don't you dare.
Oh, I'm sorry.
How do you guys even function?
You're totally nuts.
And I'm supposed to believe you're fire soldiers?
All right, fine.
You're probably going to get in trouble if you go back empty-handed.
Am I right?
I won't join your team, but I will show you something to make your trip worth it.
After that, you leave me alone.
I'm listening.
I haven't gotten to see this in a long time!
Hey, should I bring this with me or what?
Just put it down.
That's enough room.
So, what is it?
Some invention of yours?
When I was little, I made this with my dad and my granddad.
Now shut up and watch.
I want to make things people have never seen.
I won't settle for something ordinary.
Not too bad, huh?
Would you believe that there used to be over 1.7 million species of animals in the world?
This is unreal.
Those are elephants, aren't they?
What are those?
Migratory birds.
They used to fly from continent to continent.
But with the way things are now, there'd be nowhere left for them to go.
They don't understand this feeling.
But for some strange reason, I can't stop crying.
Amaterasu can only generate enough power for the Empire's people.
So I want to create a new energy source.
Something even stronger that can bring the whole world back.
And I'll bring all of the animals who went extinct back to life with it.
That's the dream I'm fighting for.
This is someone who wants to use his power to save lives.
In a way no one else can.
Captain Obi, you had the right idea.
Vulcan is perfect for Company 8.
Every time I watch, it blows me away.
So, you guys, what did you think?
Honestly, it touched my heart.
So cool.
Listen, Vulcan.
I know you'd love it at Company 8.
Please stop by.
Just talk to our captain and you'll understand.
Sorry.
Nothing you say will ever convince me to side with anyone under Hajima's thumb.
I'll find my own way.
Same thing every time.
So, how did you meet Vulcan?
Both my parents died in a fire.
An infernal destroyed my life.
Later, my relatives died too.
I was about to be put in a convent.
But the last thing I want to be is a nun.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You're not a nun, are you?
It's fine.
I ran away, straight off to nowhere.
I had nothing.
I wandered here to the scrapyard, looking for a place where I could stay out of the rain.
Then Vulcan found me and took me in.
He has a kind heart, huh?
Yeah, he does.
Too kind, maybe.
Vulcan will take in anyone who needs his help.
And animals, too.
He will work hard to take care of all of them.
Whose grave is this?
Vulcan's father's.
And his grandfather's, too.
Both of them went infernal at the same time.
That isn't something that happens often, right?
Vulcan thinks Giovanni had something to do with it.
And does he have a good reason to suspect him?
Vulcan's grandfather had taken on two apprentices.
One of them was Vulcan's father, and the other one was Giovanni.
Right after his father and grandfather died in natural deaths, Giovanni went to work for
Heijima.
That's something that was forbidden by their master.
Oh, why was it forbidden?
Something with his family.
Apparently they have a bad history with Heijima going way back.
Nice chat, but I'd better get started on Vul's dinner.
I hate to say it, but you really should give up.
Sorry, I couldn't be more helpful.
Don't say that.
We just need...
The time has come.
Vulcan must be killed.
It's that same feeling I had back in Asakusa.
That time, it was Lieutenant Conroe calling out for help.
This time, it's Dr. Giovanni out for blood.
Anyway, I think this is a bust.
Let's head back to the station and see what's next.
We can't leave Vulcan on his own right now.
Call it my hero's intuition.
It's philosophy.
As you can follow atul.
We can't leave theQUE 학.
I don't know if you're under it.
.
I'll see you next time.
Thank you.